The story of the extraordinary people who changed our world.
Fat Man and Little Boy is a drama, history, war film directed by Roland Joffé.
Assigned to oversee the development of the atomic bomb, Gen.
Leslie Groves is a stern military man determined to
have the project go according to plan.
He selects J.
Robert Oppenheimer as the key scientist on the top-secret operation,
but the two men clash fiercely on a number of issues.
Despite their frequent conflicts, Groves and Oppenheimer ultimately push ahead with two
bomb designs — the bigger "Fat Man" and the more streamlined "Little Boy."
Gen. Leslie R. Groves, played by Paul Newman.
J. Robert Oppenheimer, played by Dwight Schultz.
Kitty Oppenheimer, played by Bonnie Bedelia.
Michael Merriman, played by John Cusack.
Kathleen Robinson, played by Laura Dern.
Peter de Silva, played by Ron Frazier.
Fat Man and Little Boy (released in the United Kingdom as Shadow Makers) is a 1989 American epic
historical
war drama film directed by Roland Joffé, who co-wrote the script with Bruce Robinson.
The story follows the Manhattan Project, the secret Allied endeavor to
develop the first nuclear weapons during World War II.
The film is named after "Little Boy" and "Fat Man", the two bombs dropped on
the Japanese cities of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, respectively.
The film stars Paul Newman as Leslie Groves and Dwight Schultz as J.
Robert Oppenheimer, with supporting roles filled by Bonnie
Bedelia, John Cusack, Laura Dern, John C.
McGinley and Natasha Richardson.
The film explores themes of atomic bomb, new mexico,
world war ii, atomic bomb test, biography.
The tone is emotional.